Woodrow Wilson Collection, 1837-1986 (bulk 1883-1924 ): Preliminary Finding Aid MC168
Public Policy Papers
Woodrow Wilson Collection
1837-1986
1883-1924
Public Policy Papers
Princeton University.‏ ‎Library.‏ Public Policy Papers
Princeton University. Library. Special Collections
MC168
17 Volumes
107 boxes
43 folders
The Woodrow Wilson Collection consists of Wilson holdings which have been acquired by the Princeton University Library Special Collections gradually over many years by purchase and gifts from many sources. The collection is rich in material prior to Wilson's presidential years, although it is not limited to this period; researchers will find materials documenting both the public and private life of Woodrow Wilson. Various types of information written by or about Wilson are present in the collection, including manuscripts, addresses, articles, correspondence, telegrams, legal documents, booklets, pamphlets, photographs, portraits, cartoons, newspapers and scrapbooks.
Scope and Contents
The Woodrow Wilson Collection consists of Wilson holdings which have been acquired by the Princeton University Library Department of Collections gradually over many years by purchase and gifts from many sources. The collection is rich in material prior to Wilson's presidential years, although it is not limited to this period; researchers will find materials documenting both the public and private life of Woodrow Wilson. Various types of information written by or about Wilson are present in the collection, including manuscripts, addresses, articles, correspondence, telegrams, legal documents, booklets, pamphlets, photographs, portraits, cartoons, newspapers and scrapbooks.
The writings include addresses delivered between 1896 and 1910, as well as the transcription of Wilson's first inaugural address, written in 1913 on his own typewriter and with corrections in his own hand. Also included among the writings are notes taken of Wilson's course lectures by undergraduates, some of whom wrote down his words almost verbatim.
There is correspondence between Wilson and his family, friends, and colleagues both in academe and in the political arena. The original letters (and photostats) of the correspondence between Wilson and his first wife, Ellen Louise Axson, covering 1883 until 1913, are included. In addition, there are collections of correspondence assembled by colleagues and friends, such as Thomas Creigh, Garrett Droppers, David F. Houston, Mary A. Hulbert (Mrs. Peck), John Wesley Wescott, Lawrence C. Woods, and Frederic Yates. Also included is the Thackwell collection of correspondence between Woodrow family members and especially between Woodrow Wilson and his cousin, Harriet Woodrow, his first love, as well as photographs of both Woodrow and Wilson relatives.
Noteworthy are the many visual representations of Wilson including portraits in a number of different media, such as photographs alone and with others, pictures of family members, and the G. E. Thompson collection of photographs. The collection also contains collections of documents, memorabilia, and ephemera from throughout Wilson's life, as well as some sound recording and audio-visual material and section of printed matter including newspaper articles and printed speeches.
In the "Papers of Others" series, one finds correspondence by family members and writings about Wilson, as well as accretions to the collection by Wilson Farrand, McMillan Lewis, and Laura S. Turnbull. Included is the Henry L. Bragdon collection of reminiscences covering Wilson's years in academia as a student, professor, and university president. Also, the collection of Charles L. Swem, Wilson's stenographic secretary, of shorthand notebooks, transcriptions of speeches, correspondence, and interviews recorded from 1912-1921, makes a significant contribution to the corpus, as do the shorthand notebooks of Gilbert Close, another secretary, covering the year 1919 when Wilson was in Paris.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The audio and audiovisual portion of the Woodrow Wilson Collection is currently on one 7" reel tape, a Victor Record, and a sound film strip. Access to this material follows the Mudd Manuscript Library policy for preservation and access to audiovisual materials.
Other Finding Aids
Card indexes to "Early Axson Correspondence" and "Woodrow Wilson and Ellen Axson Wilson Correspondence" are located in drawer 530 of Series 3: Indexes of the Papers of Woodrow Wilson Project Records at the Mudd Manuscript Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection has been gradually acquired by the Princeton University Library's Special Collections through purchase and gift over many years.
Appraisal
Cartoons and etchings have been removed to Graphic Arts. A death mask by Fotunato has been placed in the Special Collections Department's collection of death masks.
Existence and Location of Copies
Photocopies from portions of the Woodrow Wilson Collection may be available in the Papers of Woodrow Wilson Project Records at the Mudd Manuscript Library.
Related Materials
This collection is part of a group of over 20 collections held at the Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library related to Woodrow Wilson, which can be located by searching for the subject "Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924" on the Princeton Finding Aids website or in the Princeton Library Main Catalog.
Please see Woodrow Wilson: A Guide to Selected Resources in the Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library for more particulars.
Bibliography
Link, Arthur Stanley, ed. The Papers of Woodrow Wilson. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1966-1994.
Bibliography
The following works were consulted during preparation of biographical note: Ambrosius, Lloyd E.. "Wilson, Woodrow"; http://www.anb.org/articles/06/06-00726.html; American National Biography Online Feb. 2000. Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters. Greenwood Press, NY. 1968. Link, Arthur S., editor. The Papers of Woodrow Wilson. Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ. 1966.
Husband and wife -- Maryland -- Baltimore.; Political science -- Study and teaching -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 19th century.; Political science -- United States.; Presidents' spouses -- United States -- 20th century.; Presidents -- United States -- 20th century.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1912.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1916.; Presidents -- United States -- Inauguration -- 20th century.; Stenographers -- United States -- 20th century.; New Jersey -- Governors -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Ephemera.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Reminiscences.; Statesmen -- United States -- 20th century. -- lcsh; League of Nations.; Princeton university; Albert I, King of the Belgians, 1875-1934; Axson, Stockton, 1867-1935; Bragdon, Henry L.; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Clémenceau, Georges, 1841-1929; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908; Close, Gilbert F.; Creigh, Thomas.; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Droppers, Garrett, 1860-1927; Farrand, Wilson, 1862-; Foch, Ferdinand, 1851-1929.; George V, King of Great Britain, 1865-1936; Glass, Carter, 1858-1946; Grayson, Cary T. (Cary Travers), 1878-1938; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; Houston, David Franklin, 1866-1940.; Houston, David Franklin, 1866-1940.; Hulbert, Mary A.; Lewis, McMillan, 1903-1974; Lloyd George, David, 1863-1945.; Marquand, Allan, 1853-1924.; Marshall, Thomas R. (Thomas Riley), 1854-1925; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; Orlando, Vittorio Emanuele, 1860-1952; Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941.; Swem, Charles L., 1893?-1956; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Thackwell, Helen; Thompson, G. E.; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954; Turnbull, Laura S.; Vanderlip, Frank A. (Frank Arthur), 1864-1937; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949; Wescott, John W. (John Wesley), 1849-1927; Wilson family; Wilson, Ellen Axson; Wilson, Ellen Axson; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Woods, Lawrence C. (Lawrence Crane), 1869-1925; Yates, Frederic
- Series 1: Writings, 1894-1919 October 27; 6 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  The collection is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  The Writings Series includes addresses, articles, and essays by Woodrow Wilson as well as proofs of Ray Stannard Baker and William E. Dodd's The Public Papers of Woodrow Wilson Series. Also included are lecture notes by various students of Wilson.
  Arrangement
  The Writings Series is organized into three sections: Writings by Wilson, which is arranged alphabetically by type of writing and title; Book Proofs, which is arranged by volume, and Lecture Notes, which are arranged alphabetically by students' last names.
  - By Woodrow Wilson, 1896 October 21-1919 October 27; 1 box
    - Addresses, 1896 October 21-1916; 1 box
      - Abstract of an address delivered at the 100th anniversary of the Lawrenceville School, 1910 June 11; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Annual Message to Congress, early draft TMs with holograph correct, 1913 December 2; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Baccalaureate (copy), 1904 June 12; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder F.3)
      - Baccalaureate (copy), 1905 June 11, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Baccalaureate (copy), 1908 June 7; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Baccalaureate (pp. 3-12 missing), 1909 June 13; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Ballot Reform, TMS (carbon), 1910 January 21; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - The Government and Business, TMs (abstract), 1908 April 3; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Inaugural Address, transcription from the original shorthand notes by Wilson, Woodrow, on his own typewriter (original), circa 1913 March 4; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Inaugural Address, transcription from the original shorthand notes by Wilson, Woodrow, on his own typewriter (xerox), 1913 March 4; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Inauguration of the president of Franklin and Marshall University, TMs Photostat, 1910 January 10; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - "It is always a very inspiring thing...," To the Princeton Alumni of Chicago, 1910 May 12; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - The Lawyer and the Community American Bar Association, Chattanooga, Tennessee, 1 TMs, 1 TMs carbon, 1910 August 31; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Meeting of the Industrial Club of Chicago in honor of Wilson (copy), 1916; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - "Princeton in the Nation's Service," delivered at Princeton's Sesquicentennial, 1896 October 21; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Articles, 1909 October-1913; 1 box
      - "Hide and Seek Politics," North American Review, 1910 May; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - "Life and Education," Nassau Literary Magazine, v. 66:167-169, 1910 October; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - "The Tariff Make Believe," North American Review, (September 1909), 1909 October; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - A further supplement to an act entitled An act concerning corporations (Revision of 1896), Draft, New Jersey Legislature, 1913; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Essay, American Economist, AMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Eulogy on the Death of Senator Bacon, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Messages, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 1)
    - Message to Teachers, TMs Photostat, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - To the House of Representatives regarding/An act to prohibit intoxicating beverages, 1919 October 27; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Notations-Envelopes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Note, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Press Release, 1915 March 4; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Quotation – No man can serve two masters ... facsimile (original at St. Paul's School, Concord, New Hampshire), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Report on the Social Coordination of the University (notes), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Statement-concerning the twin commissions, 1917 (ALS by Fosdick, Raymond B.), 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Proofs of Books in The Public Papers of Woodrow Wilson Series by Baker, Ray Stannard and William E. Dodd, dates not examined; 2 boxes
    - College and State, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Vol. I, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - College and State, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Vol. II, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The New Democracy, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Vol. I, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The New Democracy, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Vol. II, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - War and Peace, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Bibliography, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - War and Peace, edited by Baker, Ray Stannard and Dodd, William E., Vol. II, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - War and Peace, Vol. I, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes Taken by Wilson's Princeton University Students, 1894-1909; 3 boxes
    - General Observations on Lecture Notes (Files 2-12, Lecture notes taken by Woodrow Wilson's Princeton students), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jurisprudence, Anthony, R. W, 1902; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - American Constitutional Law, Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Constitutional Governament (sic), Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - English Common Law, I, Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - English Common Law II, Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Jurisprudence, Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Politics, Besore, Charles, 1901; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - International Law, Cartwright, Charles, Jurisprudence, M. Public Law, 1894; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Constitutional Law, Comin, Robert, 1897; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Jurisprudence, Comin, Robert, 1897 Public Law, Cowles, Clarence, 1898, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Jurisprudence, Dietrich, Harold E, Constitutional Government, 1909; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Constitutional Law, Fornance, Joseph K., Elements of Politics, 1904; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Jurisprudence I and II, Fornance, Joseph K, 1904; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Public Law, Constitutional Law, Jurisprudence, Halsey, Charles W, 1898; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Jurisprudence and Politics, Hilliard, Edward, 1904; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - American Constitutional Law, Constitutional Government, Price, Benjamin, 1904; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - English Common Law, Smith, H. Alexander, 1903; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Constitutional Law, Turner, E. B, 1896; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - American Constitutional Law, Constitutional Government, Vail, William P, 1902; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jurisprudence and Politics, Constitutional Government, Walker, Otis Lawrence, 1903; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - English Common Law, Jurisprudence and Politics, Walker, Otis Lawrence, 1903; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Politics, Williamson, Stanley, 1901; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - English Common Law, Volume I and II, Wright, A. Southard, 1900; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Jurisprudence and Politics, Zink, Homer C, 1903-1904; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1810-1992; 17 Volumes; 34 boxes
  The Correspondence Series includes letters, notes, and telegrams from a variety of individuals, usually to or from Woodrow Wilson (although some correspondence is between others and is related to Wilson). Perhaps the most notable portion of this series is the Wilson family correspondence, including letters between Wilson and his first wife, Ellen Axson Wilson, from their courtship through the end of her life in 1914, as well as correspondence to and from his daughters Jessie and Margaret, and his brother-in-law Stockton Axson. This series also includes a "Special Correspondence Collections" section, which contains shorthand notebooks of Wilson letters recorded by his secretary, Gilbert Close, as well as correspondence collections of other individuls close to Wilson, including Lawrence Woods, David Huston, and Mary Hulbert, as well as the Thackwell collection of correspondence between Woodrow family members and especially between Woodrow Wilson and his cousin, Harriet Woodrow. These collections include letters to and from Wilson and others. The final section of the Correspondence Series includes copies of letters in other collections.
  The Correspondence Series is organized into four sections, General A-Z, which is arranged alphabetically; Family, which is arranged by correspondence and chronologically within; Special Correspondence Collections, which is arranged alphabetically by collector name; and Copies in other Collections, which is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - General A-Z, 1810-1963; 7 boxes
    - 3 TLsS, Abrams, Kate Trenholm, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 2 printed invitations, Abrams, Kate Trenholm, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 3 invitations, Abrams, Kate Trenholm, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - TLS, Adams, John D, 1895; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - ALS, Aiken, Charles A, 1890; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - TLS, Alden, H. M, 1895; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - TLS, Alden, H. M, 1895; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - TLS, Alexander, Archibald S, 1910; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - TLS, Alexander, James W, 1904; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - ALS, Alleman, Gellert, 1898; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1 ALS, Allen, Charles Dexter, 1890; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9A)
    - 1 TLsS, Allen, Charles Dexter, 1910; 1911; 1921; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9A)
    - 1 C, Allen, Charles Dexter, 1921; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9A)
    - 1 TL (Xerox), Allen Charles Dexter, 1921; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9A)
    - Allibone, Lawrence W., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9B)
    - TLS, Ames, Butler, 1918; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 2 TLsS, Anderson, Mary, 1903; 1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - TLS, Armstrong, H. Howard, 1907; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - TLS (Photostat) by Armstrong to Robert Goheen, 1961; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Telegram, Axson, Benjamin Palmer card to Mr. and Mrs. B. P. Axson, 1921; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - TLS, Bagehot, Walter (about), 1905; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - 2 TLsS, Baker, Newton D, 1918; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1 Cablegram (draft) by Baker to General Pershing with ANS by Wilson, Woodrow, 1918; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1 copy of cablegram (draft) by Baker to General Pershing, 1918; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1 TL (carbon) by Baker to Wilson, Woodrow, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1 cablegram by General Pershing to The Adjutant General, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Baker to Wilson, Woodrow, 1923; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - ANS, regarding E. D. Balken-Balken, Edward D, 1897; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - TLS, Bannard, Otto T, 1915; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - 7 TLsS, Barricklo, William R, 1908; 1911; 1918; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - 1 AC, Barricklo, William R, 1916; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - TC (carbon) by Barricklo to Wilson, Woodrow, 1908; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - TLS, Barringer, D. Moreau, 1906; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - ALS with TL (copy), Beach, Charles F., Junior, 1891; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - TLS, Beaty, Julian, 1922; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - TLS, Beech, George R, 1910; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - TLS, Benfer, George C, 1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - TLS, Benhyam, Miss, 1916; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - TLS, Bickford, John Dean, 1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - TLS, Bingham, Hiram, 1906; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - TLS, Bishop, Wilson, Woodrow, 1907; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - TLS, Bishop, Wilson, Woodrow, 1907; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - TLS, Bissell, C. H, 1910; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - TLS, Black, William S, 1911; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - TLS, Boardman, Samuel W, 1903; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - 2 ALsS, Boggs, William E, 1893; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - 1 TLs, Boggs, William E, 1893; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - TLS, Bonton, Eugene, 1893; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - TLS, Borglum, Gutzon, 1917; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - TLS, Bremner, Robert, 1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - 22 ALsS, Bridges, Robert, 1885; 1888; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - 1 ALS by Scribner, Charles's sons to Wilson, Woodrow, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - 21 ALsS, Bridges, Robert, 1889-1892; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - 8 ALS, Bridges, Robert, 1893-1901; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - 1 LS, Bridges, Robert, 1896; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - 15 TLsS, Bridges, Robert, 1893-1902; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - 28 TLsS, Bridges, Robert, 1903-1910; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - 1 TL (carbon) by Bridges to Wilson, Woodrow (attached to letter), 1909 May 10; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - 4 telegrams by McCormick, Cyrus H., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - 1 telegram by Webster, J. E., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - 4 ALsS, Bridges, Robert, 1911-1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 15 TLsS, Bridges, Robert, 1911-1916; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 1 cablegram, Bridges, Robert, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS by Landon, Francis G., to Bridges, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS by Wilson, Edith Bolling to Bridges, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS by Wilson, Woodrow to Brooks, Frank M, 1903 November 25; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 40A)
    - TLS, Brougham, H. B, 1917; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - TLS, Brougham, H. B, 1916; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - TLS (1 xerox), Brown, J. Earle, 1898; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - 2 printed invitations, Brown, Warren A., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - 8 TLsS, Brownlow, Louis, 1915-1920; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - 6 TLs (carbons) by Brownlow to Wilson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - 1 memorandum by Brownlow to Mr. Richards, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Wilson, Woodrow and Bryan, William Jennings with ANS by Bryan, 1911; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 4 ALsS by Bryan to Wilson, Woodrow, 1912-1913; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 1 AL (copy) by Aquinaldo, Emile, to Bryan, 1912; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 1 ALS (copy) to Bryan to Aquinaldo, 1913; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 1 ALS by Bryan to Wilson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Newspaper clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - TLS, Burch, Robert L and Morton, M. B, 1913; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - TLS, Burk, Charles A. D, 1907; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - TLS (1 photocopy), Burk, Charles A. D, 1914; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - TLS (explanatory note), Burk, Charles A. D, 1914; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - TLs (by Mr. Tumulty), Burk, Charles A. D. (Bush, Charles A. D.) (Sic), 1914; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - TLS, Bushnell, Edward R, 1904; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - TLS, Caldwell, Charles Pope, 1916; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - ALS, Campbell, J. S. (James S), 1894; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)